good afternoon everyone and welcome back
to my home
today i'm in a creative mood while my
craft of choice is
usually painting i always like to
challenge myself to learn new things
today i'm working with natural fibers
since i love
the smell and texture of wool i'm always
attracted to projects that are slow
and methodical they make me feel
connected to my
[Music]
past
hmm
this project was inspired by a book
written nearly a hundred years ago
that delighted many children and adults
alike
it is about a toy rabbit that
desperately wants to be real
the rabbit belongs to a little boy and
spends much of his time in the nursery
where he befriends a rocking horse that
is very old and very wise
he explains to the rabbit that with
enough love he will become
real and when he becomes real he won't
be afraid of pain
anymore instead he will feel honored by
those feelings
that while painful remind him of the
blessing of his life
children's books are full of
surprisingly simple wisdom
[Music]
do
so
to quote the wise old rocking horse from
the velveteen rabbit
you become it takes a long time
that's why it doesn't happen often to
people who break easily or have sharp
edges
or have to be carefully kept generally
by the time you are real most of your
hair has been loved off and your eyes
drop out
and you get loose in the joints and very
shabby but these things don't matter at
all because once you are real
you can't be ugly except to people who
don't
[Music]
understand
oh
[Music]
so
children's stories fables and folklore
often
feature anthropomorphized animals these
stories hold much value to me
because my love for animals has been an
innate part of my person
since i was born in times of great
sadness in my life i found that having
to care for an animal
much like caring for a child would force
me to step outside of myself
and focus on another living being to
serve
instead of dwell on my melancholy
[Music]
so
wild animals impact me in a different
way
if you've ever had the honor of looking
straight into the eyes of a creature of
the wilderness
be it the perfectly round oculus of an
owl or the soft brown oval of a deer
moose or bear
it is an experience that stays ingrained
in your memory
it is both magical and humbling
once i found myself returning the gaze
of a great horned owl
while carrying firewood back to my
mother's home
we regarded each other for a long while
its dark eyes shocked me with a reminder
that this elegant creature
knew so many things that i could never
even begin to understand
it was a complex biology built from
countless ancestors
that had come before it had so many
skills that i would never be able to
attain
a formidable challenge to our human
perception of what it is to have higher
intelligence i encourage you to seek out
a natural area near your home
and see what animals you encounter no
matter how
commonplace or small each one has a
fascinating story to tell